I want to quickly show you the Django Admin and then touch on test briefly for how you might
run them in Django and then we'll move on to the final project practice.
The Django Admin is really one of the star features of this web framework and it's one
of the reasons why it's so popular.
It lets you easily interact with and edit our database models in a really nice UI with
very, very minimal setup.
So to use the Admin, you're going to need to create a super user.
So we do that by running Python managepy, create super user.
Don't forget the password that you set.
That will let you know a super user was created successfully.
If we go back to URLs that UI for practical blog, we'll see that there is an admin path
to find here.
You don't have to use the Admin if you don't want to, you would just leave this out.
Now that I've created a super user, I can go to my blog and instead of looking at a post,
I'm going to type in the URL slash admin and I will take me to a login page and I can
now log in with the super user that I created and it's going to take me to this interface.
Now these were created by Django automatically, but here we'll see in the blog apps blog
app are posts and I can click in here and add a post and give it a title and give it a
slog and just save it and we'll see that it was added successfully.
So when we go back to the index for our blog, there it is, that's the second blog post.
And all that I had to do to set that up was create and fill in an admin.py file because
it was already created for us, import our post model and then register it.
So admin.site.registerpost gave us all of that almost for free.
If we wanted to have Django auto-generate our slugs for us when creating a new blog post,
which I think we do because creating any slug manually is pretty annoying, we can comment
this out and instead create a class called post admin that inherits from model admin
and then register this instead.
If I save that and then refresh this page and go to our admin, and we'll notice that Django
is currently running in debug mode, that means that it's going to pick up any changes
automatically and just refresh the server, you don't want that on in production.
So just in FYI, that's a setting that you will flip and settings.py.
If you go to a URL here that doesn't exist, you're going to get a page not founder.
It's going to tell you what it was raised by and then you'll see a message at the bottom
saying you're seeing this error because you have debugged equals true in production,
you probably want to redirect to a standard 404 page.
So now if we look at our admin for post, we will see that when we make a post.
As I'm typing in a title, we'll see that the slug is generated automatically.
The cool thing about this is it skips certain words like A and that you don't really care
about for SEO.
So that is what you get with Django for free.
There's a lot more that you can do with it.
It's very powerful, but I just wanted to give you a preview.